

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Current Designation: Associate Manager - IT Total Experience: 19 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: First American India Pvt. Ltd Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance
Role: Program Mar

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: cloud, disaster management, business continuity, internal audit, qlik sense, advanced excel, cost reduction, operations improvement, strategic planning, resource optimization, data analysis, qualitative research, backup management, People Management

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section Work Experie

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

## Summary

I am in the current organization 'FAI' since last 10 years

My responsibilities have included the development of system/process, people and coordination among departments and achieve best results

I worked on SEV/ OMTI/ SDR/ BSC(Balance Score card-OMTI)/ Skill Matrix reports since last 5 years for IT all Infrastructure Developed the system for (DR)Disaster Recovery Strategy at Org level and BCP to certain extent

Designed the automation of Infra Data Protection(Backup) System

Manage Internal Audit/Compliance

Visited US twice for business-focused production discussions

Awarded as best/anytime approachable person award at Org level

Using best reporting tools Ex:Qlik Sense, Advanced Excel

Analysis and propose plans to reduce cost

Managed team's like DR/BCP, Cloud, Infra Backups, DNS, Messaging, Citrix, Unix.

Completed AWS certification, knowledge of other cloud technologies and opportunities

For one of the critical projects and audit's, I am directly working with executive team (VP and CEO)

## **Work Experience**

First American India Pvt. Ltd as Associate Manager - IT Sep 2010 to Till Date

Key Result Areas:

Planning and coordinating post-implementation and maintenance support; leading team members, allocating resources and guiding them till final delivery

Suggesting technology-based solutions for enhancing functional efficiency and achieving business excellence and managing risks and planning for contingencies to ensure minimal effect on deliverables

Managing end-to-end root cause analysis and driving operational changes, drawing upon professional concepts and recognizing job-related problems; understand the standard mission of the professional group and vision Engage in activities related to DR, BCP and Audits

I worked on SEV/ OMTI/ SDR/ BSC(Balance Score card-OMTI)/ Skill Matrix reports since last 5 years for IT all Infrastructure

Following escalations and change control processes, monitoring progress, conducting systems analysis sessions and tracing risks & mitigating the same while executing requirements study and estimation

Conducting RCA and suggesting technology based solutions for enhancing functional efficiency and achieving excellence

Facilitating meetings, project reviews, conference bridges and on-line meetings to disseminate and drive changes Preparing & presenting various daily/weekly/monthly MS reports and assessing the effectiveness of change management approach

Creating and implementing strategic implementation plan and upgrade paths for the migration of legacy core backup ticketing process systems

Coordinating with VP, Department Director, and other departmental staff to develop cloud and on-premise infrastructure and service strategies for data center operations, data storage and backups, security business continuity

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld and disaster recovery plans, server and network architecture, network monitoring systems, virtualization, renewal and replacement and desktop environment

Managing surveys and feedbacks received for customers to address problem areas and maximize satisfaction

### Turning Point Software Solutions Ltd as Senior System Engineer Apr 2009 to Sep 2010

Highlights:

Mentored team (Onshore/OffShore) and managed budget & reporting of SLA's to higher management Developed and implemented deployment procedures for production maintenance and coordinated with Engg./QA/Testing for bugs/improvements of applications. Also handled Installations/Up gradations/Testing in Pre-Productions and Production

Steered efforts in managing 6 authoritative DNS servers and 80 caching servers in 3 data centers hosting over 80,000 domains

Wrote SHELL scripts, Administration (Linux/Unix/Solaris/Mindows), generated tcpdumps on the servers for DNS traffic and analysis, the PCAP files and concluded the issues surfaced in Production environ

Played a key role in providing backend database maintenance support(Oracle/Mysql/GreenPlum/Netezza), analyzing TCPDUMP (pcap) data on production servers at run time including coordinating with Network team for DDOS attacks

# Mega Soft Pvt. Ltd. as Lead Engineer

Apr 2008 to Apr 2009

Highlights

Gained exposure in working with with R&D team on coming up releases and upgrading the same once released to production for clients like Telefonica, Sprint, US Cellular, Hutch, Manipal University Played a key role in:

- o Product support/Up gradation/maintenance for GIL client at Manipal. Updating/Modifying the shell scripts as per the changes required by clients
- Daily processing of the scripts for clients Epic and WestLink. Monthly billing process for the clients Epic and WestLink
- o Managing backend database support (Oracle/Mysql) and providing technical administration (Linux/Unix/Solaris/Mindows)

^ Back to Top

### **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Computer Science) from Sri krishnadevaraya University in 1999

PG: MBA/PGDM (Information Technology), Part time from vivekanand institute in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:
Diploma in Software Engineering
AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Professional (SAP)
ITIL Foundation

^ Back to Top

# IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
AWS, AZURE, Oracle, VMWare			
Redhat Linux, CentOS, Debian			
Ubuntu, Fedora, Solaris, FreeBSD			
Reporting, Qlik Sense, Advanced Excel			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
eBizmailer email marketing, Apache			
VMWare, ISC Bind, Hadoop			
HBase, Cassandra, MapReduce			
Flume/Sqoop			
MySQL, Oracle, Greenplum, Netezza			
Shell Scripting, Python			
Basic Java, C, Visual C++			
Pig, Hive, HTML			
DNS, DHCP, Anycast			
WINDOWS AD			
Bluecat Network Apps			
Neustar Network Apps			
eBizmailer, Kickstart, Jumpstart			
DEB/RPM Packages			
Netbackup&Networker			
Bluecat Appliances, Neustar Appliances			
Shell Scripting, PowerShell			
HashiCorp Configuration Language			
ICOVI			

J2OIA		
CDH		
PMP, TOGAF		
Terraform, Cloud Formation		

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
telugu	Expert	✓	✓	✓
kannada	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

# **Projects**

Project Title: Disaster Recovery System

Client: FA

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: FAI
Role: Domain Expert
Duration: Feb 2018 - Feb 2019
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 1

Skill Used: MS Word, MS Excel, Microsoft Office Sharepoint Server, Sharepoint Development

Role Description: Developed the complete end to end system and automation for Disaster Recovery planning,

Implementation and Management.

Project Details: Developed the complete end to end system and automation for Disaster Recovery planning,

Implementation and Management.

Project Title: Data Protection (Backups)

Client: FAI

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: FAI
Role: Domain Expert

Duration: Mar 2017 - Mar 2018
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 2

Skill Used: Unix Shell Scripting, SQL, Service First, Networker backup tool, and its integration.

Role Description: End to End

Project Details: All Backups and Backup Failures at Organization level were manually managed which needed Automation which again needed integration between ServiceFirst and Networker backup tool.

Project Title: Build Windows OS

Client: CMC Ltd.

 Nature of Employment: Full Time
 Duration: Feb 2002 - Mar 2003

 Project Location: CMC Ltd.
 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

 Role: Domain Expert
 Team Size: 6

Skill Used: C/C++ programming language using Linked Lists.

Role Description: End to End. C/C++ programming language using Linked Lists.

Project Details: While working as Faculty, this was developed using C/C++ programming language using Linked Lists.

Project Title: General Stores Products Stocks System Design/Development/Automation

Client: GTL

 Nature of Employment: Part Time
 Duration: Jan 1998 - Mar 1999

 Project Location: GTL
 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

 Role: Domain Expert
 Team Size: 3

Skill Used: FoxPro, Database Security, Backup, Data Recovery

Role Description: End to End.

Project Details: General Stores products from Manual paper process to System development for stock and cost

management. Developed from Scratch to Implementation. This was developed in FoxPro.

^ Back to Top

## **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent
Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.